Lost in our world, found in another.
John Carter is a action, adventure, science fiction
film directed by Andrew Stanton.
John Carter is a war-weary, former military captain who's inexplicably transported to the mysterious and
exotic planet of Barsoom (Mars) and reluctantly becomes embroiled in an epic conflict.
It's a world on the brink of collapse, and Carter rediscovers his humanity when he
realizes the survival of Barsoom and its people rests in his hands.
John Carter, played by Taylor Kitsch.
Dejah Thoris, played by Lynn Collins.
Sola, played by Samantha Morton.
Matai Shang, played by Mark Strong.
Tardos Mors, played by Ciarán Hinds.
Sab Than, played by Dominic West.
John Carter is a 2012 American science fiction action-adventure film directed by Andrew Stanton, written by Stanton, Mark Andrews, and
Michael Chabon, and based on A Princess of Mars, the first book in the Barsoom series of novels by Edgar Rice Burroughs.
Produced by Jim Morris, Colin Wilson and Lindsey Collins, it stars Taylor Kitsch in the title role, with Lynn Collins, Samantha
Morton, Mark Strong, Ciarán Hinds, Dominic West, James Purefoy and Willem Dafoe co-starring in supporting roles.
It chronicles the first interplanetary adventure of John Carter and his attempts
to mediate civil conflict amongst the warring kingdoms of Barsoom.
Several attempts to adapt the Barsoom series had been made since
the 1930s by various major studios and producers.
Most of these efforts ultimately stalled in development hell.
In the late-2000s, Walt Disney Pictures began a concerted effort to adapt
Burroughs' works to film, after an abandoned venture in the 1980s.
The project was driven by Stanton, who had pressed Disney to
renew the screen rights from the Burroughs estate.
Stanton became the new film's director in 2009.
It was his live-action debut, after his directorial work for
Disney on Pixar's Finding Nemo and WALL-E.
Stanton and his Pixar colleague Andrews wrote the initial draft of
the screenplay, which Chabon was brought on to revise.
Filming began in November 2009, with principal photography underway
in January 2010, wrapping seven months later in July.
Michael Giacchino, who scored many Pixar films, composed the music.
As with Pixar's Brave that same year, the film is dedicated to the memory of Steve Jobs, who
was CEO and majority shareholder of Pixar prior to Disney's acquisition in 2006.
John Carter had its world premiere at the Regal Cinemas at L.A.
Live in Los Angeles on February 22, 2012, and was released in the United States by Walt Disney Studios
Motion Pictures on March 9, marking the centennial of the titular character's first appearance.
It was presented in Disney Digital 3D, RealD 3D and IMAX 3D formats.
John Carter received mixed reviews, with praise for its visuals, Giacchino's score, and
the action sequences, but criticism of the characterization and plot.
It failed at the North American box office, but set
an opening-day record in Russia.
It grossed $284 million at the worldwide box office, resulting in a $200 million writedown for Disney, becoming one of the biggest box office bombs in
history and also becoming the film with the largest estimated box-office loss adjusted for inflation ever, losing $149–265 million.
With a total cost of $350 million, including an estimated production budget of
$263 million, it is one of the most expensive films ever made.
Due to its box office performance, Disney cancelled plans for Gods of Mars and
Warlord of Mars, the rest of the trilogy Stanton had planned.
Much of the film's failure has been attributed to its promotion, which has been
called "one of the worst marketing campaigns in movie history".
The film explores themes of princess, medallion, planet
mars, based on novel or book, escape.
The tone is thought_provoking.